My friends and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms, of course, so we are going
to implement and create our circular link at least.
So we go to the source folder and we create a new Java class called Circular
Linkage List.
OK.
And this is our class that we are going to solve the following exercises in the next videos and to manipulate
our circular linked list.
So the first exercise here in exercise number 66 and circular link list, we are asked to implement
the circular link list creating its node, and we make the print function and the main function.
OK, so first of all, we start by creating the note.
No, the class, but guys think about it.
What we need from a from the anatomy of that node, what it contains.
It contains data.
So I will create static class
node and it would contains that data that I need, which is of type and data.
You can make a type of card or type, string type, any object you need.
But we are working with integers linked lists or for this exercises.
And the following exercises are in and of type int data.
And what we need from a circle and this circle.
And this contains only data and the pointer to the next one.
But the trick behind circular linkage list and what distinguish it from the singly linked list is that
the last node referred and the reference to the first node, so it would be a circular forms a circle.
So for that, I need just a reference to the next note.
OK.
So I create a note of contains data and contains next point.
It just came.
This is how we create a class here.
Now.
I need function to insert we will see it in the previous in the next videos.
And I need a method that print and I need a driver code that make that that execution of the methods.
OK, so first of all, I will put here that so, you
know, the class.
I will put here the methods.
Methods
and I will put here.
Them and driver code or testing driver code.
We are going to create in the methods in the next exercises and the testing will start by public
static void, main
stream paths and we put here what we call the methods that we are going to see in the next few days.
Now I will create a method that will print that list printing the list.
So the first method that we are going to create is called parentless public static void print.
Last note had it took had as part of meter to start to start printing from the head till the end of
the list.
But I need to frame you to concentrate because there is a trick here.
No attempt equal to hat.
I would have to tap if head does not equal to null.
Then it is not empty.
OK.
We start by making you do system those out.
Don't.
We get the data from it by using them data glass space between it and camp that most of that next one.
So we are making a do why and do.
That moves the cursor from one to one until reaching had equal to no or temp equal to hand.
And system that allowed the print stamp does not attempt that data.
We are extracting that data from the then.
There is a trick here, guys, since we have stored them equal to had.
So we are storing.
We we checked.
This is not null.
So there is no empty list and we start printing.
We have stored temp, had the head into a temp.
Why?
Because we will start moving at the end of the list.
How to know that we have reached at the end of this circular list.
This is very important.
Thank you, guys.
Please pay attention in order to understand and to know that we have reached the end of this circular
list.
We need to compare all with the temp that we are moving from with the hat.
So if if temp does not equal to had then continue and the printing until reaching temp equal equal to
had.
So it reaches, for example.
Let me give you an example.
We have one two three four five, six, seven, eight and nine.
We start, we put here they had a temp equal to hat and we start moving using temp.
The next and the printing, OK.
Printing the data, printing, printing, printing and then reaching nine, nine.
What is the next of it?
It is one because it is circular lists.
So when temp equal to had so it when it comes again, the temp equal to had.
Then we reached the end of the circular link list.
This is the trick behind it.
OK, so this print list will cost us making all of em because it is all of that we are traversing.
We are traversing through all the elements through all that notes in the list and start printing it
using the Do Y loop.
And this will result and depends on the number of the notes and the list to be executing this method.
So it is.